(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make this fresh excitement resonate
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
The best of times, with the best of friends
キラメキ纏って イェーイ！
Clad in brilliance, yeah!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
今日は楽しんでいってください！
Please have fun today!
覚えているかな 最初の歌
Do you remember? That first song
私 声が震えていた
My voice was trembling back then
あの日から続く未来は
The future that continued from that day
みんなと掴んだ今日だよ
Is the 'today' I've grasped with everyone
もっと もっと もっと もっと
More and more and more and more
加速するハート
My heart is accelerating
行くよ どこまでも
I'm going, no matter how far
準備はOK？
Are you ready?
開け 夢の扉
Open the door to our dreams
1 2 3 キラメキライダー！
1 2 3 Kirameki Rider!
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make this fresh excitement resonate
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
The best of times, with the best of friends
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
I am here because you found me
君に会いたくてやってきたんだ
I came here because I wanted to see you
みんなで歌おう 終わらないメロディ
Let's all sing together, an endless melody
キラメキ纏って イェーイ！
Clad in brilliance, yeah!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
届いてるかな 私の声
I wonder if my voice is reaching you
届けたいのは 君に笑顔
What I want to deliver to you is a smile
いっそのこと 悔しくて
Actually, it was so frustrating
みんなと泣き笑ったね
That we cried and laughed together, right?
ギュッと ギュッと ギュッと ギュッと
Tightly, tightly, tightly, tightly
すべて抱きしめて
Holding everything close
行こう どこまでも
Let's go, no matter how far
準備はOK？
Are you ready?
進め 希望の道は
Forge ahead, the path of hope is
1 2 3 キラメキライダー！
1 2 3 Kirameki Rider!
好きな気持ちから 紡ぎカタチにしたいな
From these feelings of love, I want to weave a shape
最高の場所 最高のみんなと
The best of places, with the best of people
ここにいるよ まぎれもなく「今」
I am here, undeniably, in the "now"
君の心が幸せに染まるように
So that your heart may be colored with happiness
重ねていくハーモニー キラメキ纏って
Layering our harmony, clad in brilliance
歌い続けたいな 踊り続けたいな
I want to keep singing, I want to keep dancing
そんな願いが...
Such a wish...
わがままもいいでしょ
A little selfishness is fine, right?
だって楽しすぎて もう止まらない
Because it's so fun, I can't stop anymore
輝くステージで
On this shining stage...
もっと もっと
More and more...
お願いずっと！
Please, forever!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
嬉し楽しい愛しいだけじゃ語れない
I can't describe it just by saying it's happy, fun, and dear
今も今も悩みはあるけど
Even now, even now, I have my worries, but...
ここにいるよ 私ここにいるよ
I'm here, I'm right here
君と同じ世界を
Looking at the same world...
見つめて
As you
煌めきライダー！
Kirameki Rider!
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our fresh heartbeats resonate
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
The best time with the best companions
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
I'm here because you found me
君に会いたくてやってきたんだ
I came here because I wanted to see you
みんなとずっと
With everyone, forever
終わらないメロディ
An unending melody
煌めきに乗って
Riding on the sparkle
煌めきまとって！
Wearing the sparkle!
今日は楽しんでいってください！
Please enjoy yourselves today!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
ゔわあー！
Waaa!
あーい、ポルカだよーー！！
Ah-y, it's Polka!!
一周年ありがとうーー！！
Thank you for the one-year anniversary!!
はい、というわけで煌めきライダー、ついに歌えたー！
Alright, so I finally got to sing Kirameki Rider!
俺、歌えた！
I finally sang it!
お聞きいただきましたが...
I hope you enjoyed it...
えっと、皆さん改めてまして、一周年を迎えちゃった尾丸ポルカです！
Um, hello again everyone, I'm Omaru Polka, who has reached her first anniversary!
イェイイェイイェイ！
Yay yay yay!
どうだい一周年を迎えたポルカ、ちょっと大人になったかな？
How about it, the Polka who's reached her first anniversary, did she become a bit more adult?
まあね、いい子いい子だね君は本当に。
Well, you're a good child, really.
いい子の皆さんはハッシュタグ「#尾丸ポルカ一周年」でいっぱい呟いちゃって！
All you good kids, tweet a lot using the hashtag #OmaruPolka1stAnniversary!
お、おるよおるよ。いいね。
Oh, I see you, I see you. Nice.
楽しそうにしてまんなあ。ありがとう！
You seem to be having fun. Thank you!
もう、うーんって感じ。
Already like, 'mhm' feeling.
やべえって感じになってますけどね。
It's getting like 'whoa'.
いやー、だいぶ馴染みのあるステージになってきました、このサーカスも。
Man, I've become quite familiar with this stage, this circus too.
はい、ありがとう！
Yes, thank you!
あのね、みんなには見えないかもしれないけど、ポルカにはお前らのコメントがここにブワーってみえてるから。
You know, you might not see them, but Polka can see your comments right here, like 'whoosh'.
ブワーってみえてる。
I can see them 'whoosh'ing.
おお、いいよいいよ、書き込んじゃって書き込んじゃって！
Oh, nice, keep writing, keep writing!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
というわけで、まあ、えっと、今勢いでここまで来たけど...
So, well, uh, I've come this far on momentum, but...
ちょっとね、振り返りつつ...
Let's look back a bit...
振り返りってなんだろうね。
What exactly is looking back?
ポルカさ、もうデビューの次の日から自分のこと振り返ってばっかでさ...
Polka has been looking back on herself since the day after her debut...
振り返りがもうそろそろ分かんなくなってきてるんだけど。
So I'm starting to lose track of what looking back even means.
えーっと、ポルカさ、煌めきライダーは初めて歌ったけどさ...
Um, Polka sang Kirameki Rider for the first time just now, but...
歌枠で一体何曲ぐらい、ポルカ今まで歌ってきたんやろ一年で。
I wonder how many songs in total Polka has sung in singing streams over this one year.
ああ、ありがとうな。ずっと見てるよ。
Ah, thank you. I'm always watching.
でさ、今までポルカ何曲歌ってきたんやろこれ。
So, how many songs have I sung so far?
100曲、100は歌ったなあ。
100 songs, I definitely sang 100.
1000、1000はいってないよな、多分。
1000, probably not 1000 yet.
いない？
Anyone?
5億曲、あ、5億曲か！
500 million songs? Oh, 500 million!
ボッタクリやし...
That's a total scam/lie...
ね、200はいってるんだ。500、あ、500リアルな塩梅。
Right, I've done 200. 500? Oh, 500 is a realistic range.
じゃあ500で提出します。
Then I'll submit it as 500.
500で提出し、735曲、なんか詳細な...
Submitting 500... 735 songs? Some very specific...
あれだな、大丈夫？それ。すごい。
That, are you okay? That's amazing.
めっちゃカンニングスタイルというか具体的な。
It's like a cheating style, or rather, very specific.
はい、ということでね、5億兆万曲ということで、はい、すごい曲を歌ってきましたね。
Yes, so, 5 quintillion trillion songs, yes, I've sung an amazing number of songs.
1回のね、歌枠でね、めっちゃ歌うんよ。
In just one singing stream, I sing a lot.
ただやっぱ、こう、ね、熱意を込めて歌うってなるとさ、ガクガクになるね。
But you know, when it comes to singing with passion, it leaves you shaky.
全然すごい、ポルカ煌めきライダーできてた、ちゃんと。
It was totally great, Polka could do Kirameki Rider, properly.
煌めきに乗ってた。
I was riding on the sparkle.
煌めき纏ってた、お前らと。
I was wearing a sparkle, together with all of you.
それだったらいい。
If that's the case, then it's fine.
「頭悪い数値だな」っていうの、やめてくれませんか？
Could you stop saying, "Those are some dumb numbers"?
まるでポルカが頭悪い… でも頭悪い数値を提出したのはそっちだからね！
It's like Polka is the dumb one... but you're the ones who submitted those dumb numbers!
ポルカじゃないからね、ポルカじゃ。そっちが言ってるからね！
It's not Polka, okay? Not Polka. You're the ones saying it!
はーい！あー、良かった。
Yes! Ah, thank goodness.
あー、良かった、良かった。ありがとう、ありがとう！
Ah, thank goodness. Thank you, thank you!
というわけでね、今日はね、まあ1年を振り返ってなど、そんな可愛いこと言っておりますが。
So, today, well, I'm saying cute things like looking back over the year.
ま、実は今日はね、1年振り返り一周年とは名ばかりの…
Well, actually, today, although it's called a 1st anniversary retrospective...
地獄企画！そうね、サムネの形相からして。
It's a hellish project! Yeah, just look at the look on the face in the thumbnail.
ね、サムネイルがちょっと何か虹色で、「うわ眩しすぎて待機所が待機できないよー」とか言ってたけど。
The thumbnail is kind of rainbow-colored, and people were like, "Whoa, it's too bright, I can't wait in the waiting room!"
あのー、全然ね、あのー。
Um, not at all, um...
あ、海外ニキも！Thank you, thank you!
Ah, overseas fans too! Thank you, thank you!
No chaotic. Chaotic no. No chaotic!
Oh fantastic, amazing live! Woo!
で、即興で曲をね、あのね、作るっていうのをずっと言ってたけど。
And I've been saying for a while now that I'm going to improvise a song.
まあ、じゃあ、どうしようかな。
Well, now, what should I do?
えっと、コーナーを変えてもろて。
Um, let's change the segment.
えっと、この1年たくさん歌、歌いました。歌いましたー！
Um, I sang many, many songs this past year. I sang!
というわけでね、せっかくなんで。
So, since we're here.
ここでしか、今ここでお前としかやれないことをやりたいと思います！
I want to do something that can only be done here, now, with you!
その名も、「一周年の歌、即興で作っちゃおうぜ企画」！ドーン！
It's called the "Let's improvise a 1st anniversary song" project! Bam!
いいですねー。今日もBGMと、えー何だっけ？SEと今日もうまいことマッチした。
That's good. The BGM and, um, what was it? The SE matched up well today too.
あ、いいですね、これもなんか。
Ah, that's good too.
あ、いいね、いいね。というわけでね、今日の地獄企画は相手がいる。
Ah, nice, nice. So, today's hellish project has a partner.
そう、いうこと。なんと、なんと、なななんと！
That's right. And, and, and!
ポルカ一人じゃ一周年の歌は作れませーん！
Polka can't make a 1st anniversary song all by herself!
うぇーい！
Whey!
というわけで、えーと、ポルカ一人じゃ難しい。
So, um, it's difficult for Polka alone.
餅は餅屋、ホロはホロ屋。ん？
Every man to his trade, Holo to Holo-ya. Hm?
ホロはホロ屋。というわけでね、今日はこの方を及びしました！
Holo to Holo-ya. So, today I've invited this person!
どうぞ！
Come on out!
なんでええええええ！！
WHY?!!!
なんでなんだよおおお！
Why is it like this?!
どうしていつもデカいんだー！
Why is it always so big?!
はーい！今日はね、なんと座員くんに扮した。
Hi! Today, he's dressed as Zain-kun.
作曲家さんの「このさん」が来てくれております！イエーイ！
The composer "Kono-san" is here! Yay!
いやもうね、もう。あの座員くんに行くたいするにあたって。
Well, about him being Zain-kun.
もうね、口も取っちゃったんで今日は。
Well, his mouth came off today.
多分元々はこの方人間だったと思うんですけど、ちょっと今日は座員くんになっちゃったんで。
I think this person was originally human, but today he's become a Zain-kun.
もう何も物言わぬものとなって。ちょっとキーボード、座れる？大丈夫？
So he can't speak anymore. Can you sit at the keyboard? Are you okay?
あ、良かった、良かった。
Ah, good, good.
え、じゃあなんかさ、ほら。なんかさ、ほら、せっかくだし。
Um, then, you know. You know, since you're here.
そのちっちゃいお手手でさ、ほら。ね、このさん。
With those tiny little hands. See, Kono-san?
あ、良かった。いる、いる！おめでとう！
Ah, good. He's here, he's here! Congratulations!
今日のスペシャルゲストでございます。
He is today's special guest.
みんな、このさんのことは知っているかなー？
Does everyone know who Kono-san is?
知っているかなー？なんかピッてして。
Does everyone know? Give us a beep.
お、いいね！
Oh, nice!
なんか、合図があるとやりやすい凄え。いいなー。
It's so much easier to do with a cue. Nice.
えっと、ということでね、まあ一発で分かる。
Um, so, you'll know immediately.
と言えばポルカの枠でスーパーチャットとか読んでる時だと。
If you're in Polka's streams when I'm reading Super Chats.
多分分かりやすいのかなっていう曲が一個あるよね！
There's one song that's probably easy to recognize!
おっちゃ！
Alright!
スーパーチャットありがとう。とっても嬉しいよー！
Super Chat thank you. I'm very happy!
スーパーチャットありがとう。今日は一周年！
Super Chat thank you. Today is the 1st anniversary!
スーパーチャットが今目に入って…
Super Chat is in my eyes right now...
ないけどありがとうー！
Not really, but thank you!
大丈夫、それさ、あの、君の采配で決まるじゃん。ね。
It's okay, that, um, depends on your lead. Right?
チャンじゃないんだよ。終わらないかと思った一瞬。
It's not "chan". I thought for a second it wouldn't end.
永遠に、あの、いつもの配信のようにと思って。
I thought it would go on forever like usual streams.
あ、BGMありがとうございますね。返ってきてくれてね。
Ah, thank you for the BGM. For coming back.
ちょっと一瞬ね、エンドレス… エンドレススーパーチャットのソングが流れるかも。
For a moment... the endless Super Chat song might have kept playing.
ポルカがさ、今コメント読んだ瞬間にあのスパチャが途切れたからどうしようかと思って。
When Polka read the comment just now, the Super Chats stopped, so I wondered what to do.
あ、大丈夫です。あのね、こうやってね、あの促してるわけではないです。
Ah, it's okay. You see, I'm not, um, soliciting them like this.
こういう曲を作ってくださっている座員くんなんですよって。
I'm saying he's the Zain-kun who creates these kinds of songs.
あ、もうほら。ね、いっぱい拍手しとる、いっぱい拍手しとる、可愛いね。
Ah, look. See, everyone's clapping so much, so much. Cute.
ねー、もうこんなんなっちゃってねー。
Right? He's become like this.
こんなんなっちゃって。頑張って今日は弾いてくれるそうなんですが。
He's become like this. He says he'll do his best to play for us today.
まあ、今日は。一周年の歌。
Well, today. A 1st anniversary song.
くるるん...
Kururun...
らしいよ。
So they say.
1周年の歌をね、あの、完全アドリブなんだけど...
Regarding the 1st-anniversary song, it's completely improvised, but...
一応さ、ほら、来てもらって...
Well, I've got you here...
でももう口がないからさ、なんかさっきからキーボードでしか対話ができてないんだけど...
But since you don't have a mouth, we've only been communicating through the keyboard...
できると思う？
Do you think we can do it?
お、できるって言ってる！
Oh, he says we can!
すごいすごいすごい！
Amazing, amazing, amazing!
なんかいけそうな気がするね、これね！
I feel like we can pull this off!
ポルカが頑張るって言うよりか、このさん頑張ってって感じになってるけど...
It feels more like "Good luck, Kono-san" rather than me working hard...
じゃあまあ...
Well then...
テーマから決めるのがいいのかな、こういうのって？
Is it best to start by deciding on a theme for things like this?
どういうところから決めていこうか？
Where should we start?
何がいいのかな？
What would be good?
やっぱでも作詞はコメントとポルカとやっていきたいし...
I want to work with the comments and Polka for the lyrics...
曲はある程度なんかさ...
And for the music, to some extent...
なんかじゃテーマをください、何か。
Give me a theme, anything.
何かあるかな？
Is there anything?
嘘やん。
You're kidding.
これあれじゃん、崖の上やん、もう。
This is like that cliffhanger scene.
自白やん、これ。
This is a confession.
いや、違うの！
No, it's not like that!
あの女が悪かったのよ！
That woman was the one at fault!
私じゃない、私じゃない！
It wasn't me, it wasn't me!
もう嫌、私ここからと...
I can't take it anymore, I'm going to jump...
待て！
Wait!
君がそこで命を落として、誰が救われるというのだ？
If you throw your life away there, who will be saved?
え、でも...
But...
君がそこで命を落としたところで、何も変わらない。
Even if you lose your life there, nothing will change.
世界は変わらない、明日は続いて...あ、大丈夫です。
The world won't change, tomorrow will continue... Ah, I'm okay now.
もう一回やって？今。
Can you do that again? Right now.
これがテーマか...
Is this the theme...?
これ1周年の歌かな...
Is this really a 1st-anniversary song...?
どうして？どうして？
Why? Why?
今は多分、これを読みながら...
Right now, probably while reading this...
ポルカはいい感じの歌詞探しとくからコメントは歌詞を打って、はい！
Polka will look for good lyrics, so chat, type some lyrics, go!
いいね！
Nice!
Yo, Yo, フリースタイルラップになっちゃってるからこのままじゃ。
Yo, yo, it's turning into a freestyle rap at this rate.
誰かいい感じのテーマをください。世にも奇妙なポルの物語とか言ってんじゃねえぞ。
Someone give me a good theme. Don't say "The Strange Tale of Polka."
おいおいおい。カブトムシ。
Hey, hey, hey. A beetle.
カブトムシが怖いんだ。カブトムシが怖いんだ。
I'm scared of beetles. I'm scared of beetles.
なんか強そうじゃない？ロックっぽくない？カブトムシが怖いんだ。
Doesn't that sound strong? Isn't it rock-like? "I'm scared of beetles."
あ、いいね！なんかもうちょっとテンポ速くいくか。
Oh, nice! Let's go a bit faster with the tempo.
カブトムシが怖いんだ！なんか、サンマスターみたいな感じでいくか。
I'm scared of beetles! Let's go with a Sunmaster-like vibe.
俺はどうしてもカブトムシが怖いんだ！
I'm absolutely scared of beetles!
カブトムシ！カブトムシ！カブトムシが怖いんだ！
Beetle! Beetle! I'm scared of beetles!
どうしてどうしてカブトムシはあんなに怖いんだ！
Why, why are beetles so scary!
なんでカブトムシはあんなに怖いんだけど...
Why are beetles so scary, but...
クワガタはかっこいい！
Stag beetles are cool!
1周年の歌ちゃうやん！
That's not a 1st-anniversary song at all!
あのさ、ちょっとさ...そうそうそうそう。1周年の歌じゃないじゃん、なんか。
Listen, wait... Yeah, yeah, yeah. That's not a 1st-anniversary song.
なんかちょっともうっちょっと何かいい感じの歌詞、歌詞の案ください。
Give me some better lyrics, some lyric ideas.
とりあえずおめでたいっていうことと、ちょっとね、あのメジャー路線いこう。
For now, let's focus on "celebratory" and go with a more mainstream style.
おめで...いいねいいね、その思考中の音いいね。
Cele... Nice, nice. I like those "thinking" sounds.
なんかあの...えっと...なんかおめでたい感じの曲じゃん。
Like, you know... um... it should be a celebratory song.
えっと1周年、ポルカは頑張ってきました。
Um, 1st anniversary, Polka has worked hard.
頑張りを体現できるような歌。低気圧に勝った感じ。あ、いいね、低気圧に勝った感じ。
A song that embodies my hard work. Like overcoming low pressure. Ah, I like that, overcoming low pressure.
低気圧に勝ってポルカが1年輝いてなんか素晴らし...なんか壮大なさ...
Overcoming low pressure, Polka shining for a year, something wonderful... something grand...
なんだろう、ミュージカルじゃないけどそのなんだろうアメージングでグレースな感じのさ...
Like a musical, but like, amazing and graceful...
そういう低気圧に勝てた晴れの日の感じ。
That feeling of a sunny day after overcoming low pressure.
あ、いいねいいね！
Oh, nice, nice!
ついに生まれたよ、ポルカは...
Finally, Polka was born...
去年この日にホロライブに入り...
On this day last year, joining Hololive...
低気圧に勝った、低気圧に勝った。
Overcame low pressure, overcame low pressure.
そして明日からは、高気圧になるよ。
And from tomorrow, it will be high pressure.
高気圧って素晴らしい。
High pressure is wonderful.
これが1周年おめでたい歌よ！
This is the 1st anniversary celebratory song!
1周年...ありがと...
1st anniversary... thank you...
ありがとうー
Thank you~
できてない？これ。
Isn't it done? This.
あれ？完成したか？
Huh? Is it finished?
待って。あれ？完成した？
Wait. Huh? Is it finished?
完成したか今ので。あ、完成した！
Did it finish with that? Ah, it's finished!
やったー！完成したっぽくない？
Yay! Doesn't it seem finished?
あれ？でもこういう感じでいいのかな？
Huh? But is it okay like this?
なんかさ、打ち合わせのキーボードとさちょっとなんかまた変わってきてない？
Like, isn't it a bit different from the keyboard in the meeting?
ワンチャンちょっとあのおさ、やらせしようぜみたいなこともしたのにね。
Even though we were like, "Let's maybe fake it a bit."
なんかやらせしようぜっていうのあれだけど、やらせしてません、してません。
Saying "let's fake it" is a bit much, but we're not faking it.
してません、してません、してません。
We aren't, we aren't, we aren't.
なんかあれ、結構でもまあこれは結構進化が見えていい感じだよね。
Huh, but well, this feels good because you can see the evolution.
高気圧になったよっていう。高気圧になって、虹がかかって、
Like, "it's become high pressure." It becomes high pressure, a rainbow appears...
なんて言うんだろうな最後うまく決めたな。それだ今の感じでいくんだったらサーカス感が欲しい。
How should I say, I finished it well at the end. That's it, if we go with that, I want a circus vibe.
確かに。忘れていたこのサーカステントのサーカス感。
True. I forgot the circus vibe of this circus tent.
忘れておりましたポルカは。だからサーカステントにいた小さい尾丸ポルカが旅立ち...
Polka had forgotten. So, the small Omaru Polka who was in the circus tent sets out...
低気圧というところから、えーとバーンと行って、
From a place called low pressure, and then bang!
高気圧の素晴らしい虹がかかったとは？
A wonderful rainbow of high pressure appeared?
え？ダメか。
Huh? No good?
なんか空中ブランコに乗るサーカスぴゅーんって感じ、なんかカートゥーンミュージックぽい感じ。
Something like a circus trapeze flying "pyun", like cartoon music.
あ、難しそうやななんか。
Ah, it seems difficult.
カブトムシはもう忘れろや。いつまで引っ張っとんねん。
Forget about the beetle already. How long are you going to drag that out?
もうカブトムシの曲出てこないよポルカは。
Polka won't come up with a beetle song anymore.
気圧に負けない。もうじゃあ気圧とかそういうのどうでもいいから。
Not losing to air pressure. Well, I don't care about air pressure anymore.
あれ？おめでたい感じどこ行った？
Huh? Where did the celebratory feeling go?
サーカスで1周年でこんなにポルカ成長しました、なんかでも変わり種がいいなちょっと。
In the circus, on our 1st anniversary, Polka has grown this much. But I want something unique.
ロック？なんか戦隊ものとかさ。ジャジャーン！
Rock? Like a superhero show. Ta-da!
ジャジャーン、ジャジャジャジャーン！さあ、尾丸ポルカ、2年目に入りました尾丸ポルカ。
Ta-da, ta-da! Now, Omaru Polka has entered her 2nd year.
さあ、これからどんな戦いを見せ...
Now, what kind of battle will she show...
戦い？誰と戦うんだ一体。戦いを見せていくのか。
Battle? Who on earth is she fighting? Will she show us a battle?
いいですねこれは。何かの何かが問われていくでしょう。
This is good. Something will be questioned.
いつ歌に入りますか、この曲はいつ歌に入りますか。
When will the singing start? When will the singing start in this song?
ポルカの1年。最初暗い感じ行こう。ポルカの1年。
Polka's one year. Let's start with a dark feeling. Polka's one year.
ポルカの1年。最初は...
Polka's one year. At first...
いろんなこともあり、いろんなこともあり、低気圧があって...
There were many things, many things, there was low pressure...
歯も痛かった。歯も痛かったけど、
My teeth also ached. My teeth also ached, but...
虹色のサムネイルもありました。
There were also rainbow-colored thumbnails.
だけど！だけど！だけど！
But! But! But!
ポルカ、強くなったよ！
Polka became strong!
今日は素晴らしい尾丸ポルカ1周年！
Today is the wonderful Omaru Polka 1st Anniversary!
ハッシュタグ尾丸ポルカ1周年で呟いてくれよ！イェー！
Tweet with the hashtag #OmaruPolka1stAnniversary! Yeah!
このあとどうしよう。どう？
What should we do after this? How about it?
なんか大サビ欲しいよね。
I want a grand bridge/chorus.
ポルカのサーカス、まだ始まったばかり。
Polka's circus has only just begun.
これでいく。どう？いろいろ案出ますけど、どういう方向性でいくのが一番楽しいのかな？
Let's go with this. How is it? I'm coming up with various ideas, but which direction would be the most fun?
なんかメロディはいいのにって言われて、ポルカがダメみたいに言うな。しんみりより元気。
Saying "The melody is good but..." makes it sound like I'm the problem. Cheerful over sentimental.
でも狂気が足りないって言っている人がいて、狂気ってなんだよ？
But some people say it lacks insanity. What do you mean, "insanity"?
だいぶ狂気だろこの企画。おいおいおい。キラメキライダーではないだろ。
This project is plenty insane. Hey, hey, hey. It's not Kirameki Rider.
な、ほらもう埋まっちゃったじゃんどうすんの。嫌になっちゃったじゃん。変えたくなっちゃってるじゃんこれ。
Look, it's already buried, what are we going to do? I'm fed up. I want to change it.
ほら。お、なんだこれ。これなんか仮装大賞でよく見るやつじゃん。
See. Oh, what's this? This is like those things you see on Masquerade.
最初埋まっててドゥドゥドゥドゥドゥってやった。あ、上がってる、上がってる！
At first it's buried and then it goes "du-du-du-du". Ah, it's going up, it's going up!
入れたげてよー、もう。
Put it in already.
シシロちゃん入れたげて。
Put Shishiro-chan in.
えー、入れたげられないの？
What, you can't put her in?
じゃあ、ラミィちゃんほら、最後入れたげて。
Then, look, put Lamy-chan in at the end.
違うんだって、仮装大賞やってる場合じゃないの。
No, I'm telling you, this isn't a costume competition.
あの、ポルカいい相手を見つけてしまっちゃったからさ、こうやって。
You see, Polka found a good partner, like this.
いいおもちゃみたいなザイン君を見つけちゃったからさ、もう永遠これできるんだよ。
I found a good toy-like Zain-kun, so I can do this forever.
とりあえず、まあ...
Anyway, well...
固まってるようで固まらないし、ポルカって何でもできちゃうんだなってことが分かってきましたね、だいぶ。
It seems settled but it's not, and I've really come to realize that Polka can do anything.
キラメキジェットコースター。ちょっと待って、キラメキジェットコースター。
Sparkling Jet Coaster. Wait a sec, Sparkling Jet Coaster.
キラキラしてて...分かった！めっちゃ落ち込んでるところから急にガーン！って上げたらどう？
It's sparkling... I've got it! How about going from being really depressed to suddenly jumping up 'bam!'?
なんかさ、キラメキジェットコースターだよ、キラメキジェットコースター。
You know, it's Sparkling Jet Coaster, Sparkling Jet Coaster.
こう、やばい、なんか。最初のね、歌詞がね、最初のしんみりした歌詞が...えっと。
Like, wow, this is... The first lyrics, the first somber lyrics... let's see.
キラメキ空中ブランコ、感情のジェットコースター、感情のジェットコースター。なるほど。
Sparkling Trapeze, Emotional Jet Coaster, Emotional Jet Coaster. I see.
えっと、感情のジェットコースター。最初、だから遅刻して落ち込んだみたいな、なるほどね。
Let's see, Emotional Jet Coaster. So at first, like being depressed because of being late, I see.
ポルカは一人、ポルカは一人、ポルカは一人...
Polka is alone, Polka is alone, Polka is alone...
一人で、一人で進んでいく。
Alone, advancing alone.
でもそこには、でも辿り着いた先にはみんながいて...
But there, but at the end of where I arrived, everyone was there...
高気圧になって、虹がかかって...
Becoming high pressure, a rainbow appeared...
おおー、いいじゃん。なんかいいじゃん。
Oh, that's good. Somehow it's good.
あ、これ今沈んでるところ。沈んでるところ。ここまだ沈んでて。
Ah, this is the sinking part. The sinking part. Still sinking here.
でもまだジェットコースター下の方...で。
And still at the bottom of the jet coaster... and then.
でも！でもみんながいた！みんながいた！みんながいた！
But! But everyone was there! Everyone was there! Everyone was there!
サーカスがやれた！(ちょっとBメロやっちゃった) あー、たた...
I could do the circus! (I did the B-section a bit) Ah, ta-ta...
仲間がいるよ、もう過ちは犯さない。
I have friends, I won't make mistakes anymore.
なんとかもなんとかも突き進んで行くよ。
Pushing forward through this and that.
ヘイ！ここじゃん！いいじゃん！これめっちゃいい！
Hey! Here it is! Good! This is really good!
仲間たちに会えた！
I met my friends!
やったー！あ、さよなら。
Yay! Oh, goodbye.
やった！やっぱりポルカが一番！ポルカおるよ！ポルカおるよ！っていうのが欲しなんか。そしたらサビの...
Yay! As expected, Polka is the best! I want something like 'Polka is here! Polka is here!'. Then the chorus...
ポルカおるよ、ポルカおるか、ポルカおるよ、ポルカおるよー！
Polka is here, is Polka here, Polka is here, Polka is here!
仲間たち、夢、希望。いいね、そこら辺かな。
Friends, dreams, hopes. Nice, maybe around there.
で、落ち込んでるところは多分低気圧だから、そこから多分虹か何かが射してきて。
And the depressed part is probably low pressure, so maybe a rainbow or something shines from there.
あ、いいね。とりあえず、感情ジェットコースターはいいじゃん。感情...でもなんかちょっと待って。キラメキライダーパクりたいから、感情キラキラジェットコースターとかにしない？
Ah, nice. Anyway, Emotional Jet Coaster is good. Emotional... but wait a sec. I want to rip off Kirameki Rider, so how about Emotional Sparkling Jet Coaster?
感情...おー、えんや。これもういつまでもやれるんだけど。
Emotional... oh, it's a party. I could do this forever.
光、あ、光、いいね。光。
Light, ah, light, nice. Light.
ジェットコースターは2周目、あ、かっこいいそれ何それ。めっちゃいいじゃん。
Jet coaster is on the second lap, ah, that's cool, what's that? It's really good.
ジェットコースターは2周目、虹、サーカス、空中ブランコ、えっと、えっと...
Jet coaster is on the second lap, rainbow, circus, trapeze, um, um...
無限、無限いいネ無限。なんか、光の先へとかそういう、あ、いいじゃん。いいじゃん。
Infinite, infinite is good, infinite. Something like 'To the end of the light', ah, that's good. That's good.
あ、で最後。最後なんか夕暮れが、こう夕暮れの感じで終わっていこう。
And finally. Let's end with a sunset, a sunset feeling.
多分最初めっちゃ暗いところからいきなりガン！ってやって、大サビでめっちゃキャー！ってして、そのままピョーン！ってして感じね。
Probably starting from a very dark place then suddenly 'bam!', then a 'kya!' in the grand chorus, and then 'pyon!' like that.
できたね、もう完璧だね。サビ、サビはだからさっきのは...一回お願いします。
Done, it's perfect. Chorus, the chorus is... one more time please.
あ、描き出す虹のアーチ、描き出す虹のアーチ...
Ah, drawing a rainbow arch, drawing a rainbow arch...
でもここで君に会ったよ、やっと君に会ったよ、描き出す虹のアーチ...
But here I met you, finally met you, drawing a rainbow arch...
カブトムシは忘れないよ。
I won't forget the stag beetle.
はいり始めているそうなので、
I heard it's already starting, so...
えっと、そうですね、あの、ちょっと本格的に今は、
Well... yes, I think Kono-kun is currently...
多分頑張ってます、座員くん、ちょっと、
...doing his best for real, Kono-kun, a bit...
今、ちょっとね、一応マジのがちで作ってるから、
Right now, I'm seriously making it for real, so...
ちょっと、あと歌詞コメント、まとめといてください。
...please keep the lyrics coming in the comments.
はい、歌詞ね。今出た歌詞、ちょっとまとめといてもらって、
Yes, the lyrics. Keep the ones that just came out.
これから、ちょっと、えっと、あの、個野さんの休憩を、
And next... well, Kono-san's break...
休憩してねぇんだけどさ、今も、あの、ポルカの一応一周年なのでね、
...wait, you're not on break right now either.
Since it's Polka's 1st anniversary...
ちょっとポルカも歌って、
...may Polka sing, too?
歌って、歌っていいですか？歌います！
May I sing? I'm going to sing!
何も言わずとも！
Even if you don't say anything!
ねぇねぇ個野さん、なんかいい感じの入りをやってくれよ。かっこいい感じのさ、
Hey, Kono-san, give me a good intro.
Something cool!
DEATH!
俺も歌いたいんだーー！
I want to sing too!
違う違う違う、ごめんごめん。ちょっと乗っちゃったんだけど、
Wait, wait, sorry. I got a bit carried away.
実はね、持ってきた曲、ちょっとセクシー寄りなんだよ、この者。
Actually, the song I brought is a bit
on the sexy side.
セクシー寄りなんだよ。なんかちょっとセクシー寄りの入りってないかな？
It's on the sexy side. Is there a sexy-style intro?
逆に！
On the contrary!
いや、それは、だって。え？いいの？え？いいの？
Well, that's because... eh? Is it okay? Eh? Is it okay?
Suspect
意地悪ね 君をずっと
You're so mean. It's not like I was
見ていたわけじゃない
watching you the whole time.
僕の考えを 当ててごらんよ
Try to guess what I'm thinking.
些細なしぐさ 視線 まばたき
A subtle gesture, a glance, a blink
君はもう 手のひらに
You're already in the palm of my hand.
むき出しの罠 なんて かかるわけないわ
There's no way I'd fall for such an obvious trap.
甘い言葉にも 惑わされない
I won't be misled by sweet words.
心の奥の 奥の奥まで
To the deepest, deepest part of your heart,
見透かしちゃうよ 行くよ
I'll see right through you. Here I go!
Lookin' Seekin' Touchin' Feelin'
Seekin' Touchin' Feelin'
Ready?
自覚ないでしょうね 思い通りに
You probably don't realize it, but you're being
君は動かされている
moved exactly as I intended.
ごっと 単純じゃないの
God, it's not that simple.
駆け引きの火を
Don't miss any of the sparks
全て見落とさないで
of our bargaining.
キミと 加速してく
With you, our heartbeats
二人の鼓動
are accelerating.
心理戦は 次のステージへ
The psychological battle moves to the next stage.
映るその目に 私はどう映るの
How do I look in those eyes reflecting me?
とても煌びやかで まるでシンデレラ
So glittering, just like Cinderella.
突き刺さる視線 隙間感じて
Feeling the gap between our piercing glares,
君に余裕見せつけて
I'll show you my composure.
あからさますぎて お腹よじれるよ
You're so obvious, it's making me laugh.
既に君はもう 出来上がってる
You're already completely under my spell.
頭で次の 次の次まで 見通さなくちゃ
I have to see ahead in my mind to the
next, and the one after that.
Lookin' Seekin' Touchin' Feelin'
Ready?
唯一無二のジョーカー 手にするために
To get your hands on the one and only Joker,
欲望さらけ出してる
you're exposing all your desires.
ホット 離れていく
Hot, the logic of the world
世界のロジック
is drifting away.
君も楽しめるかな
I wonder if you can enjoy it.
キミと 重要なキーワード
With you, the important keywords
全てシークレット
are all secret.
後戻りは できないステージへ
To a stage where there's no turning back.
気づいてるでしょ ここにいる意味さえも
You've noticed, haven't you? Even the meaning
of being here.
切り札はそれぞれ 互いの手札に
The trump cards are in each other's hands.
頭と心で 暴き出して
Uncover it with your mind and heart
胸を撃ち抜け
and shoot right through my chest!
自覚ないでしょうね 思い通りに
You probably don't realize it, but you're being
君は動かされている
moved exactly as I intended.
ごっと 単純じゃないの
God, it's not that simple.
駆け引きの火を
Pick up all the sparks
全て拾って
of our bargaining.
唯一無二のジョーカー 手にすることで
By taking hold of the one and only Joker,
理解できた愛の形
I've finally understood the shape of love.
一秒でも...
Even for a second...
どこかの誰かに仕組まれていても
Even if it was orchestrated by someone, somewhere
最後に笑う君と
With you, who laughs at the end
さあ、速攻して
Now, act quickly
二人の鼓動
The heartbeat of the two of us
新見世は次のステージへ
The new performance moves to the next stage
Oh... Yeah... Ah...
パッ！ タッタララタリララタリラリラッ
Pa! Tattararatariraratatarirarira!
はぁ... はぁ... タッタララタリラリラ...
Huff... huff... Tattararatarirarira...
はぁ... うまく歌えませんでしたー！
Huff... I couldn't sing it well!
サスペクト、ありがとうございました！
Thank you for 'Suspect'!
先輩コーラスありがとうございました！
Sempais, thank you for the chorus!
この曲、めっちゃ好き！
I really love this song!
すげー練習した！
I practiced it so much!
はぁ... 歌枠でも多分歌った...
Huff... I probably sang it in a karaoke stream too...
練習してる... すげー練習した曲と...
The songs I've practiced... The ones I practiced a lot and...
練習があまりできていない曲のあれが顕著に出て... 出て... 出ている
...the ones I haven't practiced much, the difference between them shows clearly.
どうだい、君？ 良かった？ 良かった？
How was it for you? Was it good? Was it good?
サスペクトしてた？ サササッしてたね、みんな
Were you 'Suspect'-ing? You were all 'sasasa'-ing, weren't you?
サスサスしとるね、おぉ...
You're 'sasusasu'-ing, oh...
いや、ちょっと待って。大丈夫。ちょっと待って、大丈夫...
No, wait a second. It's okay. Just a moment, it's fine...
大丈夫、今頑張って多分ね、あの... 作ってると思うから、ちょっとね...
It's okay, they're probably working hard right now to create it, so just a bit...
はぁ... 頑張ったー。座員ありがとう。
Huff... I worked hard. Thank you, Zain-kun.
ちょっとね、このままで次の曲も、実はあるんですよ。ちょっと水飲むわ。
Actually, there's another song after this. I'm going to drink some water.
座員くん、よろしく。
Zain-kun, please take over for a bit.
おーい、よし。ありがとう、座員くん。
Oi, okay. Thank you, Zain-kun.
はい、ただいま。ただいま。
Yes, I'm back. I'm back.
あ、おかえりって言ってる。すごーい！
Ah, you're saying 'Welcome back'. Amazing!
意思の疎通が図れた！
We were able to communicate!
というわけで、えーと、次の曲、歌いたいですが、えーと、これは...
And so, um, I want to sing the next song, but, um, this is...
いや、言っとけよって話なんだけど...
Well, it's a case of 'you should have said so sooner'...
えーと、まぁ、この曲を一人で歌うのは、最後にしよう、したいなと思っている曲です。
Um, well, this is a song that I want to make the last time I sing it alone.
なぜむしろ逆に、ここに来るまでのこのね、ねぽらぼ1周年と書いてあるこの出発は...
Why, on the contrary, until coming here, for this starting point with 'Nepolabo 1st Anniversary' written on it...
歌っていないのだろうかっていうのが、ちょっとね、あの、不思議なくらいなんですけど...
...why haven't we sung it? It's almost strange, but...
いろんな理由とかいろんなことが忙しかったりとかして、4人で歌うことが叶わなかったんだけど...
Due to various reasons and being busy with many things, it wasn't possible for the four of us to sing it together...
ポルカ一人で今日は最後、歌ってやるぜ、これを！っていう曲で行きます。
But today, Polka is going to sing it alone for the last time! That's the song we're going with.
ありがとうございます。そう！ そう！ ナイス！ もう一回言って！ お？
Thank you. Yes! Yes! Nice! Say it again! Oh?
ん？ その手拍子は何個かい？
Hmm? How many handclaps was that?
いいね、3つなんだね。わかった。3つらしいです、手拍子は。
Nice, it's three. Got it. Apparently, it's three claps.
そう、必要なのは手だけで大丈夫！ 行くよ！ じゃあ、歌わせてください！
Yes, all you need are your hands! Here we go! Well then, please let me sing!
『BLUE CLAPPER』
'BLUE CLAPPER'
手を上げて Clap your hands 海の向こうまで
Raise your hands, clap your hands, all the way across the sea
Clap your hands 届きますように
Clap your hands, I hope it reaches you
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands
ほら、一緒にさあ！
Come on, let's do it together!
Everybody clap your hands 空の向こうまで
Everybody clap your hands, all the way across the sky
Clap your hands 響きますように
Clap your hands, I hope it resonates
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands
光射す僕たちの未来 行くぞ！ コールしろ！
To our future where the light shines. Let's go! Give me a call!
カンパイはよろしくな！
Take care of the cheers!
Three! Two! One! 行くぞ！
Three! Two! One! Let's go!
Holo-Life with stars 始めようか Starting message 未来的な Timing
Holo-Life with stars, shall we begin? Starting message, future-like timing
あの姿みたいに Swimming swimming
Like that figure, swimming, swimming
引き寄せるよ Rising まだ見えない May be
Drawing it in, rising, still invisible, maybe
この先には何があるの？
What lies ahead?
まだ早いよ Next 追いつくまで Checking
It's still too early, next, checking until I catch up
でもたまに止まって Thinking thinking
But sometimes I stop and think, thinking, thinking
変えて見せる景色 踏み出すのさ Starting 掴んでみせるよ キラキラマイデイ
The scenery I'll show you changed, I'm stepping out, starting, I'll grab it, my sparkly day
叶う日まで Sorry つなぎたいから
Until the day it comes true, sorry, because I want to connect
だって君に ずっと見てほしいから
Because I want you to keep watching me
手を上げて Clap your hands 海の向こうまで
Raise your hands, clap your hands, all the way across the sea
Clap your hands 届きますように
Clap your hands, I hope it reaches you
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands
ほら、一緒に！ Everybody clap your hands
Come on, together! Everybody clap your hands
空の向こうまで Clap your hands
All the way across the sky, clap your hands
響きますように 手を叩こう
I hope it resonates, let's clap our hands
手を叩こう 光射す僕たちの未来
Let's clap our hands, to our future where the light shines
Oh yeah!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
いっぱい手拍子してください！
Please clap your hands a lot!
今日はいらない Breaky 微成功はステキ
Don't need a breaky today, micro-success is lovely
何時でも一緒 24時中
Any time together, 24 hours a day
君は何をミリ？ 解き放て Sparking！
What are you looking at? Unleash the sparking!
暗闇に放つ Laser Beam
A laser beam released into the darkness
光らせて Stage 作るから
I'll make the stage shine
なぁ 君にもっと見てほしいから
Hey, because I want you to see more
手をあげて Clap Your Hands！ 海の向こうまで
Raise your hands and Clap Your Hands! To the other side of the sea
Clap Your Hands！ 届きますように
Clap Your Hands! May it reach you
手を叩こう！ 手を叩こう！
Let's clap our hands! Let's clap our hands!
ほら一緒に Go！
Come on, let's go together!
Everybody Clap Your Hands！ 空の向こうまで
Everybody Clap Your Hands! To the other side of the sky
Clap Your Hands！ 響きますように
Clap Your Hands! May it resonate
手を叩こう！ 手を叩こう！
Let's clap our hands! Let's clap our hands!
重なる Wave 世界を揺らせ！
Overlapping waves, shake the world!
Oh!
Yeah!
Woo!
1 2 3 4 5！ 行くぞ！
1 2 3 4 5! Let's go!
終わりがあることくらい知ってるけれど
I know that everything has an end
でもまだまだ泳ぎ足りないイライラ
But I still haven't swum enough, feeling restless
Bang！ 気まぐれし Bang！ 待てレイシー
Bang! Capricious Bang! Waiting for you
次元混ざり合う全て塗り替える Blue
Dimensions mix together, painting everything Blue
手をあげて Clap Your Hands！ 海の向こうまで
Raise your hands and Clap Your Hands! To the other side of the sea
Clap Your Hands！ 届きますように
Clap Your Hands! May it reach you
手を叩こう！ 手を叩こう！
Let's clap our hands! Let's clap our hands!
ほら一緒に Go！
Come on, let's go together!
Everybody Clap Your Hands！ 空の向こうまで
Everybody Clap Your Hands! To the other side of the sky
Clap Your Hands！ 響きますように
Clap Your Hands! May it resonate
手を叩こう！ 手を叩こう！
Let's clap our hands! Let's clap our hands!
光り射す 僕たちの未来
The future of ours where the light shines
Yeah! ハイ！ハイ！
Yeah! Hai! Hai!
最高に楽しもう！
Let's have the best time!
ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
うーーー！ありがとう！
Uhh... thank you!
めっちゃ手叩いてくれてた！
You guys were clapping so much!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
一人で歌うのは...
Singing alone...
...これが、このステージでここで歌うのはさ、最初で最後がいいな。
...I'd like this to be the first and last time I sing alone on this stage.
次は四人で立てるようにポルカめっちゃ頑張るから！
Polka will work really hard so that next time all four of us can stand here!
でも今、えっと、他のメンバーに言ってます。はい！
But right now, um, I'm telling the other members. Yes!
よし... ふぅ〜 よかった
Alright... Phew~ that was good
ありがとう
Thank you
ポルカのお歌のターンはここまでになっております
Polka's singing turn ends here
あとは、さ、コノさん
Next is, well, Kono-san
作曲だよ
It's composition time
さ、やるよ、続き
Come on, let's do the continuation
ポルカも頭回ってない...
Polka's head isn't spinning either...
「1周年の歌」を作ろう！
Let's make a "1st Anniversary Song"!
え！？なになにそれ！？ちょっと待って、待って、待って！なに！？
What!? What is that!? Wait, wait, wait! What!?
ハイ！ハイ！え、なにこれ？ちょっと待って。え、なにこれ？ちょっと待って。
Hi! Hi! Eh, what is this? Wait a second. Eh, what is this? Wait a second.
え？なに？ちょっと待って... え？なにこれ？いつ出来たのこれ？
Eh? What? Wait... Eh? What is this? When was this made?
え？え？え？ちょっと... あの... え？出来上がってるやないかい！
Eh? Eh? Eh? Wait... um... eh? It's already finished!
あの、その過程... ああ、過程はもう先の裏で、あの、バシバシやってたのがあれが過程やったんか。
Um, the process... ah, the process was what you were doing busily behind the scenes earlier? That was the process?
え？ってことはもう終わって... ちょっと待って。
Eh? That means it's already finished... wait a second.
え？でもポルカが、待って、ポルカが追いついてない。
Eh? But Polka, wait, Polka hasn't caught up.
あなたの情緒にポルカが追いついていない。最初だって下がるんだろう？下がるの？
Polka hasn't caught up with your pace. You said it would go down at first, right? Go down?
な！え？もう上がっちゃってる...
Wh-! Eh? It's already gone up...
大きくなったね、ザインくんも。すごいね、大きくなったね。
You've grown big, Zain-kun. Incredible, you've grown big.
あぁ、なるほどね。あの諸々の諸般の事情により、サビ作ろう。
Ah, I see. Due to various circumstances, let's make the chorus.
サビだけめっちゃクオリティを上げて、あとで動画で、ま、前の中... じゃ、前の部分を作ればいいじゃない？
Let's just make the quality of the chorus really high, and then later we can make the, um... well, the previous part for the video, right?
いいじゃない？サビだけじゃあ仕上げればいいじゃない？
Isn't that fine? Let's just finish the chorus then, right?
ちょっと、作詞頼んじゃなくてさ、一緒に手伝ってくれるって言ったじゃん。なんでそこで裏切るの？
Wait, I didn't ask for a lyricist, you said you'd help me. Why are you betraying me there?
先さ、ほら、なんとかのアーチとか虹がうんちゃらとか。あれ？え？だって... え？
Earlier, you know, something about an arch or the rainbow being whatever. Huh? Eh? But... eh?
カブトムシじゃない... え？同窓... そう、そう、そう。そう、あの、なんとかの虹の光... 光が夢で... あれ？
It's not a beetle... eh? Classmate... yes, yes, yes. Yes, um, the light of the rainbow or something... the light is a dream... huh?
えっと、これかも変えとけばよかった。
Well, maybe I should've changed this too.
じゃあ、虹の……
Then, the rainbow's...
虹のアーチ。
The rainbow arch.
ストップ！
Stop!
虹…… 虹がかかるステージで。
Rainbow... On the stage where the rainbow appears.
合ってる？ ふわり。
Is that right? The flow.
虹がかかるステージで。なんか一個足んねえな。
On the stage where the rainbow appears. Something's missing.
虹が…… 虹…… 虹の……
Rainbow... Rainbow... Rainbow's...
虹の……
Rainbow's...
ああ、虹の…… 虹の……
Ah, rainbow's... Rainbow's...
に、虹…… 虹きらめくステージでとかは？
Ra, rainbow... How about "On the stage where the rainbow sparkles"?
なんか小…… かな？ 虹きらめくステージで。
Is it a bit weak? On the stage where the rainbow sparkles.
笑顔を見せて…… 虹…… 虹…… 虹…… 虹がかかったステージで。
Show me your smile... Rainbow... rainbow... On the stage where the rainbow appeared.
笑顔を見せて……
Show me your smile...
お、今頑張ってるね。
Oh, I'm working hard right now.
今頑張って動かしてるんですよ。これでも、このちっちゃいおててでね、頑張って今一緒に作業しとるから。
I'm trying my best to move it. Even with these small hands, I'm working hard on this together with you.
虹が…… うん、虹の…… 虹の…… 虹のかかったステージ。
Rainbow... yeah... rainbow... On the stage where the rainbow appeared.
ステージ…… ステージで…… 虹のかかったステージで……
Stage... on the stage... On the stage where the rainbow appeared...
笑顔は？ 笑顔どこ行った？
The smile? Where did the smile go?
笑顔…… 笑顔…… 笑顔を見せるよ。
Smile... smile... I'll show you my smile.
とびっきりの笑顔を見せるよ。スマイル、えっと、きらめく……
I'll show you my best smile. Smile, let's see, sparkling...
笑顔を見せるよ。
I'll show you my smile.
キラキラの笑顔を見せるよ。
I'll show you my glittering smile.
笑顔を咲かせるよ。
I'll make your smiles bloom.
苦しいね。産みの苦しみだね、それは。
It's tough. Those are the labor pains of creation.
それは産みの苦しみなんよ。今一緒に頑張ってるからさ。
That's what it is. Because we're working hard together right now.
笑顔…… 舞台じゃなくて…… それは……
Smile... not the stage... that's...
今はね、そういうのは置いといて。
Let's put that aside for now.
あのね、これね、今何？ コンペ前の曲やから。ちょっと待っといてな。
You know, this is, what? A song before the competition. So wait a moment.
満点の笑顔をあげる。
I'll give you a perfect smile.
虹のかかったステージで満点の笑顔をあげる。
On the stage where the rainbow appeared, I'll give you a perfect smile.
ステージで…… はい！
On the stage... Yes!
虹のかかったステージで満点の笑顔をあげる！
On the stage where the rainbow appeared, I'll give you a perfect smile!
声？
Voice?
これください。
Give me this one.
なんとかのかんとかのかんとかのかんとか。
Something something something something.
走り、走り出すよ。
Running, I'll start running.
急に走りたがり。走り出すよ。
Suddenly wanting to run. I'll start running.
走り出すよ。
I'll start running.
どんな時でも……
No matter when...
えっと…… えっとな……
Let's see... let's see...
や、YAGOOしか出てこない今。頭の中に。すごいや頭の中にYAGOOが出てくる。
No, only YAGOO comes to mind now. In my head. YAGOO keeps popping up in my head.
なんでだろう？ な、埋まるな、埋まるな！ 大丈夫か？ 元気出して。
I wonder why? Don't, don't bury yourself! Are you okay? Perk up.
ああ、走り出すよ。2年目もまたね。なるほどね。
Ah, I'll start running. See you again in the second year. I see.
2年目もまた……
The second year too...
それが感情のジェットコースター！
That's the roller coaster of emotions!
フリーフォールじゃないとか言ってなんか。それが……
Saying it's not a freefall or something. That's...
それが感情のジェット…… なんか感情ってなんか、なんかちょっとごつくない？
That's the roller coaster of emo... Doesn't "emotions" sound a bit heavy?
ジェットコースターはいいんだけどなー。
The roller coaster part is fine, though.
低気圧にも負けずにジェットコースター。どう？
A roller coaster that doesn't lose to low pressure. How about that?
なんかテンションジェット…… あ、テンションジェットコースター！
Like tension jet... oh, Tension Roller Coaster!
いいね、テンションジェット。
That's good, Tension Roller Coaster.
お、決まったきたきたきたきた！ じゃあフルで歌えんじゃね？ 歌うぞ！ 行け！
Oh, the decision's made! Then, I can sing the full version, right? I'm going to sing! Go!
虹のかかったステージで満点の笑顔をあげる！
On the stage where the rainbow appeared, I'll give you a perfect smile!
走り出すよ2年目もまた。感情のジェットコースター！
I'll start running, into the second year too. The roller coaster of emotions!
走り出したもう止まらない。尾丸ポルカ2年目もまた。
Once started, I won't stop. Omaru Polka, in the second year too.
頑張るよみんなに届け。この気持ち伝えたい！
I'll do my best to reach everyone. I want to convey these feelings!
動画にするよ。
I'll make it into a video.
これは動画にするから。
Because I'm making this into a video.
でもテープの、デモデモデモ、デモテープでした。
But it was just a de- de- de- demo tape.
いや、頑張ったよ。
Man, I worked hard.
頑張ったよ俺ら。
We did our best.
このさん、ありがとう。
Kono-san, thank you.
ありがとうな！
Thank you!
いや、頑張りましたー！
Man, I worked hard!
満点！
Full marks!
というわけで！
And so!
じゃあ、こちらは1周年の歌を作ろう。
Well, that was the "Let's Make a 1st Anniversary Song" corner.
ま、タイトルもね、ちょっと後で考えるとして。
Well, I'll think of a title later.
まあ今後に期待ということで。
So, please look forward to it in the future.
そのコーナーでした。ありがとうございました！
That's it for that corner. Thank you very much!
というわけで、このさん、今日はありがとう。
So, Kono-san, thank you for today.
ホタテのヒ... (笑)
The scallop's... (laughs)
雑にはけさせちまった。一番今日頑張ってたのに。
I let him leave so abruptly, even though he worked the hardest today.
はい、というわけで、ちょっと自分でツボっちまった。
Yes, and so, I'm cracking myself up.
はい、ここでなんと、告知をしたいと思います。
Yes, and now I'd like to make an announcement.
というわけで、尾丸ポルカ1周年配信どうでしたか？
So, how was the Omaru Polka 1st Anniversary stream?
まだまだ #尾丸ポルカ1周年 で呟いちゃってね。
Keep on tweeting with the hashtag #OmaruPolka1stAnniversary.
もうコメントも拾う余裕もないので。
I don't even have time to read comments, so...
じゃあ、ここでいきなりですが。
Now, this is a bit sudden, but...
お知らせです！はいドン！
It's time for an announcement! Here it is!
尾丸ポルカ活動1周年記念！
Omaru Polka 1st Anniversary Celebration!
こちら、8月16日、この後9時からBOOTHにて販売させていただきます！
These will be on sale at BOOTH today, August 16th, starting from 9 PM!
素晴らしいことに変わりはねえんだけどさ。すごいやろ？すごいやろ？
It's just as amazing as ever. Isn't it great? Isn't it great?
今回はなんと、あかもく先生にイラストをお願いしております。
This time, we've commissioned Akamoku-sensei for the illustrations.
はい、じゃあ続きのドン！こちら！
Yes, and here's the next one! This!
ポルカおるよ、等身大タペストリー。
"Polka is Here" life-size tapestry.
存在感ですかね。
It's all about the presence.
あかもく先生に、すげえ存在感のあるポルカくださいっていうことで。
I asked Akamoku-sensei for a Polka with a really strong presence.
これ153cmのポルカがお前の家に行くよ、っていう感じ。
This 153cm Polka is coming to your house.
なんでポルカ貼るものがめっちゃ好きなんだろうね。
I wonder why I like things you can put on walls so much.
クローゼットとかガッと開けたらさ、「わあ、ポルカおったわ」みたいな。
Like when you open your closet and you're like, "Whoa, Polka's here!"
これね、ポルカ見た。とりあえず3個ぐらい部屋に貼ってみたけど。
I saw it. I tried putting up about three in my room for now.
賑やか。
It's lively.
一気に家族が増えたっていう感じになっちゃって。
It feels like my family suddenly grew.
抱き枕とかとは全然違った感じになるけど。触り心地が良かった！
It's a totally different feel from a hug pillow. It felt great to the touch!
というわけで続いてはこちら。
Anyway, here's the next one.
はい、みんなお待たせ！座員くんぬいぐるみだよ！
Yes, sorry to keep you waiting, everyone! It's the Zain-kun plushie!
耳の再現度やばすぎ。笑った。
The detail on the ears is insane. It's so funny.
一番のこだわりはこの、くり抜きのハートです。
My biggest point of focus is this cutout heart.
ハートの部分がね、ちゃんと縁取りにされてるから。
The heart part is properly bordered.
なんと丈夫。
It's surprisingly sturdy.
みんなもこうやって口のないものになってしまおうということで。
I guess we're all going to become mouthless things.
こちらは何個あってもいいね。
You can never have too many of these.
根っことサイズが良い感じだった。
The base and the size were just right.
まだまだありますよ、こちら！
There's still more! This!
フルセットの特典は、尾丸ポルカからの...
The full set bonus is... from Omaru Polka...
複製手書きお手紙！
A replica handwritten letter!
手書きお手紙です！
It's a handwritten letter!
さっきTwitterで「ポストカードあるんやったら額縁買わなあかんな」みたいな人見て。
I saw someone on Twitter saying, "If there's a postcard, I've gotta buy a frame."
ただお手紙、ポルカ好きなんだよね。
But I really like letters.
万年筆で書くのがすごい好きだから、ぜひこれを受け取ってほしい。
I love writing with a fountain pen, so I really want you to have this.
記念ボイスはちょっと変わった趣向のいろんなボイスになってるから。
The commemorative voices have various themes, so...
それもまたBOOTHのページで見てください。
Please check those out on the BOOTH page as well.
というわけで、ありがとうございました。こんな感じです。
Anyway, thank you very much. That's about it.
大大大、大満足だと思います。
I think you'll be very, very, very satisfied.
いつも「戦争が大変だ」とか言ってる人たち、焦らず焦らず。
For those who always say "it's a war to get them," don't rush, don't rush.
ポルカは逃げないよ。ポルカはここにオルよ。
Polka won't run away. Polka is right here.
あ、急ですが、そろそろお別れです。
Oh, it's sudden, but it's almost time to say goodbye.
そろそろお別れの雰囲気出します。
I'll start setting the mood for the ending.
ポルカ1周年、あっという間に過ぎ去ってまいりました。
Polka's 1st anniversary has flown by in the blink of an eye.
あー、やー。この後は、
Ah, yeah. After this,
えっと...
well...
IDの子たちが新衣装もあるし大変なんだよ！
the ID girls have their new outfits,
so it's a big deal!
え？
Huh?
なんか終わりの雰囲気コメントで出して。
Everyone, give off some "ending" vibes
in the comments.
はい, 悲しいですがもうそろそろお別れの時間です。
Yes, it's sad, but it's almost time
to say goodbye.
悲しいですがそろそろお別れの時間です。
It's sad, but it's almost time to say goodbye.
お、元気だBGMが今日も。はは！
Oh, the BGM is lively today too. Haha!
お、あれ？お、お、お。いい感じ。
Oh, what? Oh, oh, oh. Feels good.
まあね、まあ、
Well, well,
お、お、なんか時差がある？ ポルカとなんか場内の座員くんスタッフと。
oh, oh, is there a lag? Between Polka and the staff in the venue.
えっと、今日はそれだけじゃないぞ。
Um, that's not all for today.
この後終わってからねぽらぼの動画も上がっちゃうんだぞ。
After this ends, a NepoLabo video
will also be uploaded.
そっちは15分からチェックしてね。
Check that one out starting from 15 minutes past.
今はまだシルエットになってるけど、 まあ楽しみにしといてくんなまし。
It's still just a silhouette now,
but please look forward to it.
でもでも、その後なぜか半から謎の「ぽ」という動画が 上がっているわけですが。
But but, after that, for some reason, a mysterious
video called 'Po' will be uploaded at half past.
こちら予想がついている方は予想がついていて、 予想がついてない方はついてなくて尾丸ポルカはポルカです。
For those who can guess what it is, you've guessed it,
and for those who can't, you haven't,
and Omaru Polka is Polka.
というわけで、
And so,
初披露のオリジナル曲をみんなに聴いてもらいたいと思います！
I'd like everyone to hear
my first-ever original song!
ポルカね、これね... えっ、ちょっと待て、言い訳から入らせて。
Polka, you see, this one...
Wait, let me start with an excuse.
BPM333なんだ。
The BPM is 333.
ちょっとポルカ歌えないからさ、ちょっとDJブースカモン！
Polka can't really sing it, so...
DJ booth, come on!
というわけさ。はは！
That's how it is. Haha!
ちょっとねポルカが盛り上げながらみんなにこの曲の楽しさを 知ってもらうため、
Polka will pump things up
while letting everyone know how fun this song is,
えっと、オリジナルの曲をやっちゃいますよ！
so, I'm gonna do my original song!
というわけで、準備はいいかな？
So, are you ready?
テンションぶち上げ音圧マックス音量最大！
Get your tension up,
sound pressure to the max, volume at the highest!
ギュイイイイイン！
Gyuuuuuuuuuun!
聴いてください、オリジナル曲、
Please listen to my original song,
ぽ！
Po!
ぽ！ぽ！ぽぽぽぽぽ！
Po! Po! Po-po-po-po-po!
やっほー！
Yappoo!
ポルカだよ〜
It's Polka~
って、
Wait,
なんか、声が変じゃない？
is my voice weird?
ぽぽぽ... あー〜〜
Po-po-po... Ahhhhhhh
聞こえますか〜
Can you hear me~?
聞こえてくれ〜〜
Please hear me~~
お〜〜い
Oooooooi
だめか
No good, huh?
このままずっと
Am I going to stay like this
ぽで生活するのか？
and live as 'Po' forever?
やだな〜
I hate that~
なんかあっちにあるぞ？
Is there something over there?
よくわかんないけど、
I'm not sure what it is,
とりあえず行ってみよー
but let's go for now.
なんか怖いとこに出たぞ
I've come out in a scary place
暗いし寒いし
It's dark and cold
嫌だな〜
I hate this~
うーん
Hmm
どっちかなあ
Which way is it?
今度はあっちに行ってみよ〜
Let's try going that way this time~
ぽぽぽぽぽ！
Po-po-po-po-po!
うわあ
Whoa
絶対道間違えたわ...
I definitely took the wrong turn...
落ちたら死ぬやん
I'll die if I fall
そんなわけないやろ
That can't be right
悪い夢なら覚めてくれ〜
If it's a bad dream, wake me up!
ん？
Huh?
なんか音が聞こえる？
Can I hear a sound?
うわあ！
Whoa!
なんかやっぱりこっち来る！
Something is coming this way after all!
にげにげ！
Run, run!
にーげーろー！
Ruーーn!
あの光の向こうへ！
To the other side of that light!
にーげーろー！
Ruーーn!
ぽぽぽぽぽ！
Po-po-po-po-po!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
このあと, えっと, 12時から
After this, um, starting from midnight,
こちら楽曲配信するよーって言うのを
this song will be available for streaming,
スタッフさんに出してって言うのを忘れてた。
but I forgot to tell the staff to put that notice up.
iTunes Apple Music Spotify 等で順次配信予定 配信開始日 2021/8/17 0:00〜
Scheduled for distribution on iTunes, Apple Music, Spotify, etc. Streaming starts: 2021/8/17 0:00~
ぽぽぽぽぽ！
Po-po-po-po-po!
いっちねん
1st Anniversary
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
おつポルカ！
Otsu-Polka!
ありがとねー！
Thank you!